<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The night-bell-man of Pickadilly to the Princess of Denmark. Welcome great princess to this lovely place ...</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1693</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B04490</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing N1153A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R224513</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">53299201</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 53299201</idno>
            <idno type="VID">179942</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B04490)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 179942)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2808:47)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The night-bell-man of Pickadilly to the Princess of Denmark. Welcome great princess to this lovely place ...</title>
                  <author>Nottingham, Daniel Finch, Earl of, 1647-1730.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1693]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Place and date of publication suggested by Wing (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Frederika Amalie Oldenburg, --  Princess of Denmark, 1649-1704.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  Foreign relations --  Denmark --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Denmark --  Foreign relations --  Great Britain --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-06</date>
            <label>Emma (Leeson) Huber</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Rekeyed and resubmitted</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:179942:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 13 -->
            <head>THE <hi>Night-Bell-Man</hi> OF PICKADILLY TO THE Princeſs of Denmark.</head>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>elcome great</hi> Princeſs <hi>to this lovely Place</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>here</hi> injur'd Loyalty <hi>muſt hide its Face;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ur praiſe each day by every Man is ſung,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>d in the Night by me ſhall e'er be rung.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>God bleſs your</hi> Queen, <hi>and yet I may moreover</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Own you</hi> our Queen <hi>in</hi> Berkly-ſtreet <hi>and</hi> Dover.</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>May your great Prince and you live numerous years,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>That's the subject of all our Loyal Prayers.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <div type="response">
               <head>My Lord <hi>Nottingham</hi>'s Orders to Mr. <hi>Dieves</hi> late Clerk of the Council, upon notice of the aforeſaid Verſes.</head>
               <p>YOU are to take a Meſſenger with you, and find out the Dwelling-houſe of the Bell<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man of <hi>Pickadilly,</hi> and when you meet with him, ſearch his Fur Pocket, his Night<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>, and above all his Bell, exactly; and what-ever Verſes or Copies of this, or any other <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>ure you find, ſeal them up very ſafely, and bring them to me.</p>
               <p>You are ſtrictly to examine him, Whether he be the true Author of them? Or, who was that that made, and gave them to him, and who ordered him to ſing or ſay them, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> what reward he got for ſo doing.</p>
               <p>You are alſo to enquire of him, Whether he hath ever heard of my Letter, by the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>een's Commands, to the Major and Aldermen of the <hi>Bath,</hi> upon another Subject, though <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>h of the ſame Nature.</p>
               <p>You are to demand of him (if ſhe confeſſeth it) how he durſt preſume do That ſo near <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> Court, which the Mayor and Aldermen of the <hi>Bath</hi> were forbid to do at ſo great a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>ance.</p>
               <p>You are privately to acquaint him (if he ſaith he never heard of it) with the true Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> of her Majeſties diſpleaſure with the Princeſs. which I herewith give you in writing.</p>
               <p>You are to charge him, upon pain of her Majeſty's high diſpleaſure and the forfeiture <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>is Employment, that he do not preſume for the future to ſing any Verſes, or ſay any <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>ds about thoſe Streets of the ſame Nature, without our Licenſe firſt obtained.</p>
               <p>You are to charge him not to pay that Ceremony to the Princeſs, in his Night-walks, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>e uſually does to the reſt of her Majeſties Subjects, that are not under her Majeſties <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>eaſure.</p>
               <p>You are to charge him to take care that Thieves and Robbers be apprehended; but <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> that part of his duty to the Princeſs; for ſince her Guards are taken off, ſhe is neither <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> regarded by day, nor ſecured by Night.</p>
               <p>You are to acquaint him, that her Majeſties diſpleaſure is ſo great againſt the Princeſs the Government deſigns to ſtop her Revenue, and by that means to ſtarve her (as well <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> any other <hi>Jacobites</hi>) into an humble ſubmiſſion to the Government.</p>
               <p>You are from him to go to Dr. <hi>Birch,</hi> and charge him, as he will anſwer it before <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>race at <hi>Lambeth,</hi> not to introduce <hi>New Ceremonies</hi> of bowing in time of Divine Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> (it being contrary to his own Education, the Example and Tradition of his Fathers; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>ally when his Superiours are ſo buſie about aboliſhing the Old Ones; warning him <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>ularly to keep cloſe to his Text, and his Text cloſe to himſelf, and that he permit no <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> elſe to handle the ſame.</p>
               <p>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>d, laſtly, you are to acquaint both the Bellman and Parſon, that her Majeſty expects <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>act compliance herein, as a publick mark of their Duty: But as for the Waytes, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>, Fidlers, and others, Orders ſhall be ſent to Mr. <hi>Killigrew</hi> about them.</p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
